Guide to the Romanov Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1894-1935; Series II; 6.5; (7 boxes)
  - ALBUMS
    - Album 2, 1912-13 (Box 2, Folder 101)
      Prince Valdemar of Prussia, the King and Queen of Sweden, the centenary of the Battle of Borodino, visit to Sarov, Spala (Poland). For a detailed listing, see the Appendix.
    - Album 3, 1909-15 (Box 3, Folder 102)
      Sevastopol', Levadiia, Kosmodemiansk, Peterhof, events surrounding World War I, Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich, Empress Alexandra treating war wounded. For a detailed listing, see the Appendix.
    - Album 4, 1909-10 (Box 4, Folder 103)
      Polish postcards, Sevastopol', Livadiia, parade at Tsarskoe Selo, pressed flower (between pp. 31-2), the Emir of Bokhara
    - Album 5, 1908-09 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      P. A. Stolypin, Poliarnaia zvezda, Aleksandriia, Ropsha, Tukhol'm, Biorke, Pavlovsk, Peterhof, parade at TSarksoe Selo, Pukion Sari, Prince Feliks IUsupov, Krasnoe Selo, Sevastopol', Livadiia, Orianda
    - Album 6, 1907-09 (Box 6, Folder 105)
      Peterhof, TSarskoe Selo, Pavlovsk, Revel' (Tallinn), Pukion Sari, drawings
    - Album 7, 1910-11 (Box 7, Folder 106)
      Peterhof, Sevastopol', Yalta, St. Petersburg, Prince George of Greece, Pavlovsk, trip to Germany (Friedberg, Cronberg, Bad Homburg, Hesse)
  - LOOSE PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Portraits of Individuals
      - Alexandra, Empress, signed, with inscription to Nicholas II, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - Elisaveta, Grand Duchess, signed, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 108)
      - Ioann Konstantinovich, Grand Duke, inscribed, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 109)
      - Mikhail Aleksandrovich, Grand Duke, signed, 1906 (Box 8, Folder 110)
      - Rasputina, Mariia Grigor'evna, inscribed to Mr. Brewster, with envelope, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Other
      - Grand Duke Aleksei and the Grand Duchesses Anastasiia, Mariia, Ol'ga, and Tat'iana (Box 8, Folder 112)
        Photograph is a postcard. On verso ALS to Mr. Collins from "Little [Migy?]"
      - House of Anna Vyrubova, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 113)
- Other Papers, 1910-1918; Series III; 0.2; (1 box)
  - AUTOGRAPH ALBUM
    - Album by Imperial family and members of court (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - ARTWORK
    - Alexandra, Empress
      - Decorated, hand-written prayer cards, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 115)
      - Drawing, paper, 1915 May 11 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Irina Aleksandrovna, Grand Duchess
      - Drawing, watercolor on paper, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 117)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 6; (6 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 2 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Box 3 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Box 4 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Box 5 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - Box 6 (Box 14, Folder 122)
  - Box 7 (Box 15, Folder 123)